Guide to the Henry Geldzahler Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Restricted Fragile, 0.25; (1 box)
  Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Computer disks, 2 (Box 51)
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
- November 2007 Acquisition, circa 1994-2004; 2; 3.75; (5 boxes)
  Gift of Jonathan Geldzahler, 2007.
  Sound and video recordings, compact discs relating to Peter Rosen's 2005 documentary of Henry Geldzahler, Who Gets To Call It Art?
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 1008.
  Arrangement
  Material arranged largely by format.
  Boxes 44-50 (audiocassettes, videocassettes, and CDs): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Reels 52-65 (motion picture film): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Videocassettes
    - Geldzahler04, "Painter's Painting" (Part 1), 1999 November 18; YCALMSS684_0015; 1; 01:04:48; A timecode runs through the length of the video. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349223)
    - Geldzahler05, "Painter's Painting" (Part 2), 1999 November 18; YCALMSS684_0016; 1; 00:59:28; A time code runs through the entire video. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349231)
    - Geldzahler06, Audio Selects (Part 1) (Geldzahler Voiceovers, Speeches), 1999 November 19; ycalmss684_0017; 1; 01:07:06; There is audio only on this tape. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349249)
    - Geldzahler07, Audio Selects (Part 2), 1999 November 19; YCALMSS684_0018; 1; 00:20:05; There is only audio on this tape. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349256)
    - Geldzahler11, Photo Animation, 1999 November 17; YCALMSS684_0019; 1; 00:52:00; Camera Master (tape) (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349264)
    - Geldzahler13, Birth of the Flag (Parts 1&2) (Claus Oldenberg Happening), 2000 April 6; YCALMSS684_0020; 1; 00:37:52 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349272)
    - Geldzahler16, CR #1-6 (Film to Tape Transfers of 16mm), 2001 March 14; YCALMSS684_0021; 1; 01:01:35 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349280)
    - Geldzahler17, CR #6-9, 2002 October 2; YCALMSS684_0022; 1; 00:46:13 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349298)
    - Geldzahler18, CR #10-13, 2002 October 2; YCALMSS684_0023; 1; 00:46:07 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349306)
    - Geldzahler20, CR #17-20, 2002 December 10; YCALMSS684_0024; 1; 00:32:39 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349314)
    - Geldzahler21, CR #21-24, 2002 December 10; YCALMSS684_0025; 1; 00:45:14 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349322)
    - Geldzahler22, CR #25-28, 2004 May 26; YCALMSS684_0026; 1; 00:47:06; Audio continues for about four minutes at the end of the video over black. (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349330)
    - Geldzahler09, Screen Test (2nd Reel) (Andy Warhol Screen Test of Geldzahler) [Betacam SP], undated (Box 45)
    - Geldzahler12, Warhol Archival [Betacam SP], undated (Box 45)
    - Geldzahler15, Audio Selects (Geldzahler Voiceovers, Phone Logs) [Betacam SP], 2000 July 14 (Box 45)
    - Geldzahler23, Ivan Karp Interview [Betacam SP], 2004 April 13 (Box 45)
    - Geldzahler24, Ivan Karp/George Lois Interview [DVCAM], 2004 April 13 (Box 45)
    - Geldzahler25, George Lois/Calvin Tomkins Interview [Betacam SP], 2004 April 13 (Box 45)
    - Geldzahler26&27, Calvin Tomkins Interview [DVCAM], 2004 April 13 (Box 45)
    - Geldzahler28&28A, Jonas Mekas Interview [DVCAM], 2004 June 11 (Box 45)
    - Geldzahler29, Jonas Mekas Interview [DVCAM], 2004 June 11 (Box 45)
    - Geldzahler43A, "America's Pop Collector" (PARTS 1&2) [DVCAM], undated (Box 45)
    - Geldzahler52A, George Lois Interview (PART 1) [Betacam SP], undated (Box 45)
    - Geldzahler55, Ellsworth Kelly Interviews, undated; YCALMSS684_0027; 1; 00:34:30 (Box 44, Item barcode 39002102349348)
    - Reel # 4(I) Fox Lorber "Painter's Painting", undated; YCALMSS684_0028; 1; 01:02:58 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002102349355)
    - Reel # 4(II) Fox Lorber "Painter's Painting", undated; YCALMSS684_0029; 1; 00:06:49; A timecode runs across the top of the video. (Box 46, Item barcode 39002102349363)
    - Reel # 5 Fox Lorber "Painter's Painting", undated; YCALMSS684_0030; 1; 00:57:25; A timecode runs through the entire video at the top of the screen. (Box 46, Item barcode 39002102349371)
    - Reel # 8 "Super Artist Andy Warhol", 2000 February 11; YCALMSS684_0031; 1; 00:21:00 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002102349389)
    - Reel # 9 Screen Test Henry Geldzahler, 1999; YCALMSS684_0032; 1; 00:15:20; A timecode runs at the top of the video. (Box 46, Item barcode 39002102349397)
    - Reel # 10 Jonas Mekas Print, undated; YCALMSS684_0033; 1; 00:22:44 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002102349405)
    - Reel # 11 (part 1) "Henry" Photo animation, 2000 February 4; YCALMSS684_0034; 1; 00:45:25 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002102349413)
    - Reel # 13 (part 1 of 2) "Birth of the Flag", 2000 April 4; YCALMSS684_0035; 1; 00:39:17 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002102349421)
      Copyright 1974
    - Reel # 14 "Henry" Photo Death Print, 2000 April 4; YCALMSS684_0036; 1; 00:16:26 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002102349439)
  - Sound recordings, 1999, 2002
    - Artist Interviews [audiocassette], 4 (Box 47)
  - Who Gets To Call It Art? Audio Mixes [CD] (Box 47)
  - Motion picture film
    - Descriptions from original film reel boxes, 2002; 14 (Box 48)
    - "Henry", 2002; (14 reels)
      - "Henry", 2002; 1 (Box 60)
      - "Henry", 2002; 1 (Box 62)
      - "Henry", 2002; 1 (Box 65)
      - "Henry", 2002; 1 (Box 64)
      - "Henry", 2002; 1 (Box 63)
      - "Henry", 2002; 1 (Box 59)
      - "Henry", 2002; 1 (Box 58)
      - "Henry", 2002; 1 (Box 57)
      - "Henry", 2002; 1 (Box 56)
      - "Henry", 2002; 1 (Box 55)
      - "Henry", 2002; 1 (Box 54)
      - "Henry", 2002; 1 (Box 61)
      - "Henry", 2002; 1 (Box 53)
      - "Henry", 2002; 1 (Box 52)
- June 2008 Acquisition, 2005-2006; 3; 0.25; (1 box)
  Gift of Peter Rosen, 2008.
  Who Gets to Call it Art? DVD with promotional material.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 1027.
  - Who Gets to Call It Art?, directed by Peter Rosen [commercial DVD], 2005 (Box 49)
  - Who Gets to Call It Art?, postcard (Box 49)
  - Who Gets to Call It Art?, spiral bound scrapbook of reviews (Box 49)
- October 2009 Acquisition, 1994; 4; 0.25; (1 box)
  Gift of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 2009.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 1228.
  - "Gathering of Family and Friends, 1935-1994: The Metropolitan Museum of Art", 1994 October 3; YCALMSS684_0037; 1; 01:07:58 (Box 50, Item barcode 39002102370286)